Finding Aid for the Daniel C. Prince Papers and S.T.A.R. Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Daniel C. Prince Papers and S.T.A.R. Collection
2002
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0415
40.22 linear feet
Scope and Content Note
The Self Taught Artist Resource Collection (STAR), late 1960’s-2002, are the working papers of Daniel C. Prince, Prince Art Consultants, and STAR, a 501(c)3 non-profit organization created by Daniel C. Prince. These include materials relating to artists, art environments, patrons, general correspondence, both for-profit and non-profit businesses, manuscripts of writings, research materials, publication materials, art organizations, ethnographic materials, clippings and subject files, photographs, slides and negatives, and assorted audio and video media. The collection is extensive, with the bulk of the materials from the 1990’s, though the collection continues to grow. Major topics of interest include folk art, outsider artists, self-taught artists and research on various forms of self-taught art.
Dan Prince has been assiduous in his collecting. His tireless search to discover and promote new self-taught artists has created as a by-product a large collection of materials. Without a brick and mortar gallery, Dan has relied on photographs to circulate and to sell an artist’s work. Perhaps the materials of greatest importance in this collection are the artist files and photographs, which provide a visual record of self-taught art in America. Artists of note are Howard Finster, Robert E. Smith, Danny Dowler, Karolina Danek, and Ann Krasner, as well as more famous artists such as Bessie Harvey, Mose Tolliver, Thorton Dial, Sanford Darling, and Grandma Moses. Of particular interest in this collection is the series on folk art environments. There is information on many such environments from around the country and several articles that Dan Prince wrote in support of these fragile works, some of which no longer exist.
There are three separate series relating to business materials. The material relating to Prince Art Consultants has been separated from the materials concerning STAR and the creation of the non-profit organization. The third series contains patron files. While correspondence is often a primary series in manuscript collections, the correspondence in this collection generally remains within artist, patron, or project files. There is however a small series of correspondence, both outgoing and incoming. This correspondence is in general business related, though there is plenty of personal material included.
The organizations and events series is noteworthy. It contains exhibit and gallery materials and information relating to museums, art centers and folk art organizations. There is material concerning exhibits for which Dan Prince has been curator as well as invitations to exhibits and gallery openings.
The collection contains a small series of publications by various writers. There is, however, a considerable amount of material in the writings series. The sub-series, articles, lectures, manuscripts, notebooks, and novels contain a wide-ranging variety of writing subjects. The articles, lectures, and several of the manuscripts tend toward a more academic nature. The remaining manuscripts and the novels are fiction. The notebooks are draft copies of the articles, manuscripts, novels, and correspondence.
There is a small series of personal and biographical material, though information on Dan Prince can easily be extracted for the collection as a whole. A small series of ethnographic materials relates to Dan Prince’s interest in Ethnographic Arts, which are often related to folk art and self taught art. The last paper series is Subject Files. In general there is a wealth of information to be gathered from this series. There are lesser artists and minor self-taught genres represented as well as topical information on an array of Dan Prince’s interests. The bulk of the material is newspaper and magazine clippings.
The multi-media nature of this collection is truly one of it’s strong points. The collection contains, many thousand photographs and slides, illustrating artists works as well as documenting folk art environments, community projects, and exhibits. There are audio cassettes, video cassettes, and various other media all to enhance the researchers understanding of self-taught art.
- Artist Files
  - Abelleira, Carmen (Box 1, File 1)
  - Acero, Myriam (Box 1, File 2)
  - Acuff, Roy Neill (Box 1, File 3)
  - Adams, Jerry (Box 1, File 4)
  - Adams, Judy (Box 1, File 5)
  - Agostine, John (Box 1, File 6)
  - Ahrens, June Finley (Box 1, File 7)
  - Aiken, Gayleen (Box 1, File 8)
  - Almon, LeRoy (Box 1, File 9)
  - Ambrose, Anne (Box 1, File 10)
  - Anderson, Lois (Box 1, File 11)
  - Archambault, Gregg (Box 1, File 12)
  - Arluk, George (Box 1, File 13)
  - Armitis, Michael (Box 1, File 14)
  - Armistead, Larry (Box 1, File 15)
  - Asserfea, Indra (Box 1, File 16)
  - Avey, Jaena (Box 1, File 17)
  - Baeder, John (Box 1, File 18)
  - Bajaj, Bindu (Box 1, File 19)
  - Bannister, Bradford (Box 1, File 20)
  - Barstow, Donna (Box 1, File 21)
  - Basom, Fred (Box 1, File 22)
  - Bathija, Jyoti (Box 1, File 23)
  - Bell, Dominick (Box 1, File 24)
  - Benner, Mark (Box 1, File 25)
  - Berndt, Christa (Box 1, File 26)
  - Birnbaum, Aaron (Box 1, File 27)
  - Black, Calvin (Box 1, File 28)
  - Bocchetta, Ralph (Box 1, File 29)
  - Boland, Judy (Box 1, File 30)
  - Bond, Milton (Box 1, File 31)
  - Borders, Carol Lee (Box 1, File 32)
  - Bosley, Tyrone (Box 1, File 33)
  - Brewer, Stacey (Box 1, File 34)
  - Brice, Freddie (Box 1, File 35)
  - Broadus, Raymond (Box 1, File 36)
  - Broadway, Clyde (Box 1, File 37)
  - Browne, Berkley (Box 1, File 38)
  - Brundege, Jeff J. (Box 1, File 39)
  - Bruno, Elena (Box 1, File 40)
  - Burger, Robert (Box 1, File 41)
  - Burwell, Vernon (Box 1, File 42)
  - Castel, Larry (Box 1, File 43)
  - Chalikis, Fran (Box 1, File 44)
- Artist Files
  - Cipri, Phillip (Box 2, File 1)
  - Cipri, Ray (Sunshine) (Box 2, File 2)
  - Cirtanic, Marilyn (Box 2, File 3)
  - Clark, Larry (Box 2, File 4)
  - Cloar, Carroll (Box 2, File 5)
  - Coins, Raymond (Box 2, File 6)
  - Collins, Jackson (Box 2, File 7)
  - Cosby, Elaine (Box 2, File 8)
  - Cotrona, George (Box 2, File 9)
  - Coughlin, Geoffrey R. (Box 2, File 10)
  - Covello, Joseph (Box 2, File 11)
  - Cowan, John E. (Box 2, File 12)
  - Cravens, Richard (Richard C.) (Box 2, File 13)
  - Crowell, Harold (Box 2, File 14)
  - Danek, Karolina (Box 2, File 15)
  - Danek, Karolina (Box 2, File 16)
  - Daniels, Virgil (Spot) (Box 2, File 17)
  - Daniels, Virgil (Spot) (Box 2, File 18)
  - Darling, Sanford (Box 2, File 19)
  - Davidson, Lee (Box 2, File 20)
  - Davies, Caroline (Box 2, File 21)
  - Davis Vestie (Box 2, File 22)
  - Davison, Herb (Box 2, File 23)
  - DeClet, Pedro (Box 2, File 24)
  - Del Rio, Jose (Box 2, File 25)
  - DeLuca, Ray (Box 2, File 26)
- Artist Files
  - DeMarco, Joe (Box 3, File 1)
  - Denice, Thomas (Box 3, File 2)
  - Densmore, M. (Box 3, File 3)
  - Dial, Thorton Sr. (Box 3, File 4)
  - Digney, Jerry (Box 3, File 5)
  - Dowler, Danny (Box 3, File 6)
  - Dowler, Danny (Box 3, File 7)
  - Dowler, Danny, Deposition from Dorit Dowler and Dr. Carl Rutt in a letter from Danny, with Resume (Box 3, File 8)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Unit 1 (Box 3, File 9)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Unit 2 (Box 3, File 10)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Unit 3 (Box 3, File 11)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Unit 4 (Box 3, File 12)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Unit 5 (Box 3, File 13)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Unit 6 (Box 3, File 14)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Unit 7 (Box 3, File 15)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Unit 1 Incomplete (Box 3, File 16)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Unit 2 Incomplete (Box 3, File 17)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Unit 3 Incomplete (Box 3, File 18)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Unit 4 Incomplete (Box 3, File 19)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Unit 5 Incomplete (Box 3, File 20)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Unit 6 Incomplete (Box 3, File 21)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Unit 7 Incomplete (Box 3, File 22)
- Artist Files
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Units 1 and 2 Early Version (Box 4, File 1)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Chapters 61-69 (Box 4, File 2)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Chapters 73-76 (Box 4, File 3)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Chapters 76-78 (Box 4, File 4)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Chapters 79-82 (Box 4, File 5)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Chapters 83-87 (Box 4, File 6)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Chapters 88-89 (Box 4, File 7)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Appendix (Box 4, File 8)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Appendix Materials (Box 4, File 9)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Unit and Chapter Headings (Box 4, File 10)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Fragments (Box 4, File 11)
  - Dowler, Danny, Autobiography Fragments (Box 4, File 12)
  - Dowler, Danny, Pen Pal Letters (Box 4, File 13)
  - Dowler, Danny, Internet Transcripts (Box 4, File 14)
  - Dowler, Danny, Slide Show Listing (Box 4, File 15)
  - Dowler, Danny, Computer Programming Information (Box 4, File 16)
  - Dowler, Danny, Dan Prince’s Article Research (Box 4, File 17)
- Artist Files
  - Dowler, Danny, Drafts of Article on Danny Dowler (Box 5, File 1)
  - Duquette, Tony (Box 5, File 2)
  - Earl, Gary (Box 5, File 3)
  - Easterwood, Russell (Box 5, File 4)
  - Edmondson, Will (Box 5, File 5)
  - Elf, Shari (Box 5, File 6)
  - Erath, Paul (Box 5, File 7)
  - Evans, Don (Box 5, File 8)
  - Fain, Moira (Box 5, File 9)
  - Feldman, Lester (Box 5, File 10)
  - Ferrario, Paola (Box 5, File 11)
  - Fiala, Robin (Box 5, File 12)
  - Finster, Howard (Box 5, File 13)
  - Finster, Howard (Box 5, File 14)
  - Fire, Irene (Box 5, File 15)
  - Fleischman, Greg (Box 5, File 16)
  - Fox, Mara (Box 5, File 17)
  - Fragoso, Sylvia (Box 5, File 18)
  - Fuller, Leon (Box 5, File 19)
  - Galey (Box 5, File 20)
  - Gevas, Sophia (Box 5, File 21)
  - Gibbs, Don (Box 5, File 22)
- Artist Files
  - Gibson, Sybil (Box 6, File 1)
  - Gilpin, Robert (Box 6, File 2)
  - Goertz, Augustus III (Box 6, File 3)
  - Goldman, Gale (Box 6, File 4)
  - Gonzalez, Steve (Box 6, File 5)
  - Goodman, Tifony (Box 6, File 6)
  - Gordon, Mary (Box 6, File 7)
  - Gottlieb, T. Stephanie (Terry) (Box 6, File 8)
  - Grandma Moses (Box 6, File 9)
  - Green, Homer (Box 6, File 10)
  - Greene, Mary (Box 6, File 11)
  - Grice, Eddie (Box 6, File 12)
  - Grisham, Skip (Box 6, File 13)
  - Guyther, Tony (Box 6, File 14)
  - H., Kristin L. (Box 6, File 15)
  - Hadin, Chris (Box 6, File 16)
  - Hanna, Richard (Box 6, File 17)
  - Hardin, Joe (Box 6, File 18)
  - Harris, Ben (Box 6, File 19)
  - Harris, Jeff (Box 6, File 20)
  - Harvey, Bessie (Box 6, File 21)
  - Hayes, Richard (Box 6, File 22)
  - Hennessey, Heidi (Box 6, File 23)
  - Hernandez, Jorge (Box 6, File 24)
  - Hill House Residents (10 Riverside Avenue) (Box 6, File 25)
  - Holden, Mike (Box 6, File 26)
  - Holley, Lonny (Box 6, File 27)
  - Holmes, Juliet (Box 6, File 28)
  - Hudson, Walter Tiree (Box 6, File 29)
  - Jackson, Vincent (Box 6, File 30)
  - Jarrett, Alvin (Box 6, File 31)
  - Jennings, James Harold (Box 6, File 32)
  - Johnson, Melinda (Box 6, File 33)
- Artist Files
  - Jordan, John (Box 7, File 1)
  - Kahn, Samuel (Box 7, File 2)
  - Kane, Andy (Box 7, File 3)
  - Katz, Hal (Box 7, File 4)
  - Kaye, Beverly (Box 7, File 5)
  - Keith, Ron (Box 7, File 6)
  - Keller, Karl (Box 7, File 7)
  - Kids in Crisis (Box 7, File 8)
  - Killion, Helene (Box 7, File 9)
  - King, Mary Ann (Box 7, File 10)
  - Kingdon, Donald R. (Box 7, File 11)
  - Klein, Mary (Box 7, File 12)
  - Koffler, Dr. Arthur (Box 7, File 13)
  - Krasner Ann (Box 7, File 14)
  - Krasner Ann (Box 7, File 15)
  - Krasner, Ann (Box 7, File 16)
  - Kresky, Mike (Box 7, File 17)
  - Kristoff, Jessica (Box 7, File 18)
- Artist Files
  - Laga, William (Box 8, File 1)
  - Landis, Joan (Box 8, File 2)
  - Langrock, David (Box 8, File 3)
  - Langrock, David - Assorted Materials on Langrock (Box 8, File 4)
  - Langrock, David - Assorted (Box 8, File 5)
  - Langrock, David - John Quincy Adams (Box 8, File 6)
  - Langrock, David - Grover Cleveland (Box 8, File 7)
  - Langrock, David -Dwight D. Eisenhower (Box 8, File 8)
  - Langrock, David -Dwight D. Eisenhower (continued) (Box 8, File 9)
  - Langrock, David - Millard Fillmore (Box 8, File 10)
  - Langrock, David - Andrew Jackson (Box 8, File 11)
  - Langrock, David - Thomas Jefferson (Box 8, File 12)
  - Langrock, David - Lyndon B. Johnson (Box 8, File 13)
  - Langrock, David - Abraham Lincoln (Box 8, File 14)
  - Langrock, David - Franklin D. Roosevelt (Box 8, File 15)
  - Langrock, David - Harry Truman (Box 8, File 16)
  - Larson, Lennert (Box 8, File 17)
  - Laurent, Marguerite (Box 8, File 18)
  - Leeds, Eileen (Box 8, File 19)
  - Lewis, Karamaya (Box 8, File 20)
  - Librizzi, Ray (Box 8, File 21)
- Artist Files
  - Light Family (Joe, Hosea and Mosea) (Box 9, File 1)
  - Livingston, Calvin (Box 9, File 2)
  - Livingston- Broome, Helen (Box 9, File 3)
  - Lloyd, Winnie (Box 9, File 4)
  - Long, Woodrow Wilson (Woodie) (Box 9, File 5)
  - Low, Cynthia (Box 9, File 6)
  - Lowry, Arthur (Box 9, File 7)
  - Lynch, Kenneth (Box 9, File 8)
  - Maddox, Suzanne (Box 9, File 9)
  - Madison (Box 9, File 10)
  - Manley, Roger (Box 9, File 11)
  - Marinko, George (Box 9, File 12)
  - Mark, Stephie (Box 9, File 13)
  - Materson, Raymond (Box 9, File 14)
  - Mazur, Dr. W. P. (Wladyslaw) (Box 9, File 15)
  - McCarthy, Justin (Box 9, File 16)
  - McCray, Ed (Box 9, File 17)
  - McNellis, Laura Craig (Box 9, File 18)
  - McNulty, James (Box 9, File 19)
  - Middleton, Ralph (Box 9, File 20)
  - Miettenin, Tyyne (Box 9, File 21)
  - Miller, William (Box 9, File 22)
  - Mockel, Axel (Box 9, File 23)
  - Montes, Jessie (Box 9, File 24)
  - Morgan, Kazuko (Box 9, File 25)
  - Morse, Bruce (Box 9, File 26)
- Artist Files
  - Mr. Rick (Box 10, File 1)
  - Muller, Manfred (Box 10, File 2)
  - Murphy, Cordia (Box 10, File 3)
  - Murray, Velma Murphy (Box 10, File 4)
  - Naumann, Dana Baldwin (Box 10, File 5)
  - Naylor, Colin (Box 10, File 6)
  - Naylor, Kyle (Box 10, File 7)
  - Neil, T. J. (Box 10, File 8)
  - Nemoitin, Jacob (Box 10, File 10)
  - Neuharth, Gary (Box 10, File 10)
  - Newman, Monnie (Box 10, File 11)
  - Nickens, Bessie (Box 10, File 12)
  - O’ Keefe, Margaret (Box 10, File 13)
  - O’Neil, Peter (Box 10, File 14)
  - Oscar, Leslie (Box 10, File 15)
  - Panzarella, Frank (Box 10, File 16)
  - Panzarella, Paula (Box 10, File 17)
  - Pardo, Rosita (Box 10, File 18)
  - Parks, Gordon (Box 10, File 19)
  - Pawlovsky, Ellia (McInnes) (Box 10, File 20)
  - Pelner, Greg (Box 10, File 21)
  - Peoples, Mary (Box 10, File 22)
  - Perry, Eugene (Box 10, File 23)
  - Petersen, Leonard James (Box 10, File 24)
  - Pierce, Warren (Box 10, File 25)
  - Pitt, Paul (Box 10, File 26)
  - Polan, Michele (Box 10, File 27)
  - Polk, Mrs. N. H. (Box 10, File 28)
  - Polysorbate 60, Richard (Box 10, File 29)
  - Posluszny, Frank (Box 10, File 30)
  - Powell, Dickie (Box 10, File 31)
  - Preisser, Ella (Box 10, File 32)
- Artist Files
  - Prince, Daniel C. - Assorted (Box 11, File 1)
  - Prince, Daniel C. – CD Cover Design Proposal for John Hiatt (Box 11, File 2)
  - Prince, Daniel C. – Exhibition Proposals (Box 11, File 3)
  - Prince, Daniel C. – Miscellaneous Color Photocopies of Artwork, Exhibits, and Proposals (Box 11, File 4)
  - Prince, Daniel C. – Murals- Helping to Help (Box 11, File 5)
  - Prince, Daniel C. – Murals- Life in America (Box 11, File 6)
  - Prince, Daniel C. – Murals- Sight of Music (Box 11, File 7)
  - Prince, Daniel C. – Murals- Sight of Music (Box 11, File 8)
  - Prince, Daniel C. – Stamford Cultural Development Corporation Proposal (Box 11, File 10)
  - Prince, Daniel C. – Vanderbilt University Law School Installation Proposal (Box 11, File 10)
  - Prince, Daniel C. – Vanderbilt University Proposals (Box 11, File 11)
  - Quatch, Cam (Box 11, File 12)
  - Ragir, Tanya (Box 11, File 13)
  - Ramavatram, Sathya (Box 11, File 14)
  - Ray, Jefferey D. (Box 11, File 15)
  - Reif, Max (Box 11, File 16)
  - Rice, W.C. (Box 11, File 17)
  - Richard, Deveron (Box 11, File 18)
  - Rimland, Mark (Box 11, File 19)
  - Roberg, Robert (Box 11, File 20)
  - Romano, Joe (Box 11, File 21)
  - Rosen, Seymour (Box 11, File 22)
  - Ross, Alexander (Box 11, File 23)
  - Ross, Bob (Box 11, File 24)
  - Roussel, Mary Ruth (Box 11, File 25)
  - Ruley, Ellis (Box 11, File 26)
  - Ryan, Stephen (Box 11, File 27)
- Artist Files
  - Salvatore, Joseph Anthony (Tony Joe) (Box 12, File 1)
  - Saussy, Ci Ci (Box 12, File 2)
  - Schaefle, Kristy (Box 12, File 3)
  - Schatmeyer, Gary Neil (Box 12, File 4)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) (Box 12, File 5)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit File 1 (Box 12, File 6)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit File 2 (Box 12, File 7)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit File 3 (Box 12, File 8)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit File 3 (cont.) (Box 12, File 10)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit File 3 (cont.) (Box 12, File 10)
- Artist Files
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit File 3 (cont.) (Box 13, File 1)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit File 4 (Box 13, File 2)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit File 4 (cont.) (Box 13, File 3)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit File 4 (cont.) (Box 13, File 4)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit File 4 (cont.) (Box 13, File 5)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit, Photocopies of Material Bernard Schatz Wanted Returned (Box 13, File 6)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit, Photocopies of Material Bernard Schatz Wanted Returned (Box 13, File 7)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit, Photocopies of Material Bernard Schatz Wanted Returned (Box 13, File 8)
- Artist Files
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit, Photocopies of Material Bernard Schatz Wanted Returned (Box 14, File 1)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit V. Tuttle and Dan Prince, March 1998- April 1998 (Box 14, File 2)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit V. Tuttle and Dan Prince, May 1998- August 1998 (Box 14, File 3)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit V. Tuttle and Dan Prince, September 1998- December 1998 (Box 14, File 4)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit Correspondence and Related Material (Box 14, File 5)
  - Schatz, Bernard (L-15) – Lawsuit V. Tuttle and Dan Prince Misc. Materials (Box 14, File 6)
  - Schilling, Christine (Box 14, File 7)
  - Schwartz, Shinyung (Box 14, File 8)
  - Scott, Lorenzo (Box 14, File 10)
  - Scruggs, Mary B. (Box 14, File 10)
  - Secon, David (Box 14, File 11)
  - Secq, Caroline (Box 14, File 12)
  - Segal, Roy (Box 14, File 13)
  - Serl, Jon (Box 14, File 14)
  - Sesow, Matt (Box 14, File 15)
  - Shanahan, Jim (Box 14, File 16)
  - Shane, Sue (Box 14, File 17)
  - Shaw, Janet W. (Box 14, File 18)
  - Shular, Kim Williams (Box 14, File 19)
  - Sidofsky, Hannah (Box 14, File 20)
  - Sims, Bernice (Box 14, File 21)
  - Sloane, Karel (Box 14, File 22)
  - Sloane, Ronald (Box 14, File 23)
  - Slonem, Hunt (Box 14, File 24)
- Artist Files
  - Smith, Jeff (Box 15, File 1)
  - Smith, Lillian (Box 15, File 2)
  - Smith, Matthew I. (Box 15, File 3)
  - Smith, Robert E., Correspondence, 1986 (Box 15, File 4)
  - Smith, Robert E., Correspondence, 1987 (Box 15, File 5)
  - Smith, Robert E., Correspondence, 1988 (Box 15, File 6)
  - Smith, Robert E., Correspondence, 1989 (Box 15, File 7)
  - Smith, Robert E., Correspondence, 1990 (Box 15, File 8)
  - Smith, Robert E., Correspondence, 1991 (Box 15, File 10)
  - Smith, Robert E., Correspondence, 1992 (Box 15, File 10)
  - Smith, Robert E., Correspondence, 1993 (Box 15, File 11)
  - Smith, Robert E., Correspondence, 1994 (Box 15, File 12)
  - Smith, Robert E., Correspondence, 1995 (Box 15, File 13)
  - Smith, Robert E., Correspondence, 1996 (Box 15, File 14)
  - Smith, Robert E., Correspondence, 1997 (Box 15, File 15)
- Artist Files
  - Smith, Robert E., Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 16, File 1)
  - Smith, Robert E., Correspondence, 2002 (Box 16, File 2)
  - Smith, Robert E., Correspondence Miscellaneous (Box 16, File 3)
  - Smith, Robert E., Stories (Box 16, File 4)
  - Smith, Robert E., Stories (Box 16, File 5)
  - Smith, Robert E., Stories (Box 16, File 6)
  - Smith, Robert E., Stories (Box 16, File 7)
  - Smith, Robert E., Stories (Box 16, File 8)
  - Smith, Robert E., Stories (Box 16, File 9)
  - Smith, Robert E., Stories (Box 16, File 8)
  - Smith, Robert E., Stories (Box 16, File 9)
  - Smith, Robert E., Stories (Box 16, File 10)
- Artist Files
  - Smith, Robert E., Stories (Box 17, File 1)
  - Smith, Robert E., Stories (Box 17, File 2)
  - Smith, Robert E., Autobiography Volume 1 (Box 17, File 3)
  - Smith, Robert E., Autobiography Volume 2 (Box 17, File 4)
  - Smith, Robert E., Books (Box 17, File 5)
  - Smith, Robert E. (Box 17, File 6)
  - Smith, Robert E. (Box 17, File 7)
  - Smith, Robert E., Vanderbilt University Commission (Box 17, File 8)
- Artist Files
  - Smith, Robert E., Stories for Gallery Exhibitions and one song (Box 18, File 1)
  - Smith, Robert E., Gallery Identification (Box 18, File 2)
  - Smithberger, Dana (Box 18, File 3)
  - Snyder, Bill (Box 18, File 4)
  - Sorrento, Lamar (Box 18, File 5)
  - Sparrow, Simon (Box 18, File 6)
  - Speller, Henry (Box 18, File 7)
  - Staples, Paul (Box 18, File 8)
  - Steen, Lee (Box 18, File 9)
  - Stoick, Rod (Box 18, File 10)
  - Streeter, Vannoy (Box 18, File 11)
  - Strelakos, George (Box 18, File 12)
  - Stummer, Janis (Box 18, File 13)
  - Sudduth, Jimmy Lee (Box 18, File 14)
  - Thompson, Michael (Box 18, File 15)
  - Thomsen, Arrahiwana (Box 18, File 16)
  - Tolliver, Mose (Box 18, File 17)
  - Tompkins, Betty (Box 18, File 18)
  - Toole, Maggie (Box 18, File 19)
  - Toy, Randy (Toyzini) (Box 18, File 20)
- Artist Files
  - Traylor, Bill (Box 19, File 1)
  - Treat, Rose (Box 19, File 2)
  - Turner, John (Box 19, File 3)
  - Turrentine, Carol (Box 19, File 4)
  - Tygart, Nelson (Box 19, File 5)
  - Unfasung, T. Holly (Box 19, File 6)
  - Vakili-Taleghari, Nasser (Box 19, File 7)
  - Van Maanen, Gregory (Box 19, File 8)
  - Veber, Suzan (Box 19, File 9)
  - Verene, Chris (Box 19, File 10)
  - Virgous, Felix (Box 19, File 11)
  - Vogel, Stanford Lewis (Box 19, File 12)
  - Walker, Inez (Box 19, File 13)
  - Wallace, Clyde (Box 19, File 14)
  - Webb, Lillian (Box 19, File 15)
  - Webb, Troy (Box 19, File 16)
  - Weinreich, Susan (Box 19, File 17)
  - Wilensky, Alexander (Box 19, File 18)
  - Wilkinson, Knox (Box 19, File 19)
  - Williams, Darryl (Box 19, File 20)
  - Wolpert, Lauren (Box 19, File 21)
  - Woodruff, Kristina (Box 19, File 22)
  - York, Rhawn (Box 19, File 23)
  - York, Rhawn - Lawsuit against Charles E. Tuttle (Box 19, File 24)
  - York, Rhawn - Lawsuit against Charles E. Tuttle (Box 19, File 25)
  - York, Rhawn - Lawsuit against Charles E. Tuttle (Box 19, File 26)
  - York, Rhawn - Lawsuit against Charles E. Tuttle (Box 19, File 27)
  - York, Rhawn - Lawsuit against Charles E. Tuttle (Box 19, File 28)
  - York, Rhawn - Lawsuit against Charles E. Tuttle (Box 19, File 29)
- Artist Files
  - Zeldis, David (Box 20, File 1)
  - Zeldis, Malcah (Box 20, File 2)
  - Zimmerman, Eleanor (Box 20, File 3)
- Environments
  - Black, Cal - Possum Trot and the Fantasy Doll Show (Box 20, File 4)
  - Chand, Neck - Sculpture Garden (Box 20, File 5)
  - Damonte, Emanuel “Litto” - Hubcap Ranch (Box 20, File 6)
  - Ehn, John - Old Trapper’s Lodge (Box 20, File 7)
  - Finster, Howard - Paradise Garden (Box 20, File 8)
  - Glade, Albert - Enchanted Garden (Box 20, File 9)
  - Greco, John - Holyland USA (Box 20, File 10)
  - Greco, John - Holyland USA (Box 20, File 11)
  - Greco, John - Holyland USA (Box 20, File 12)